Vendim Polisi

Expertise

Software Engineer

Vendim Polisi is Software developer with fullstack experience, backend services and frontend in React. Experienced on building native mobile apps in behalf of React Native and Expo. Worked on migration services and ETL processing logic on data warehouse (Python). He has strong ability to communicate with clients, colleagues and all levels of management. Able to perform ongoing development and maintenance of the company's corporate Internet and Intranet web sites in support of the company's internal and external communications objectives. Currently assisting in development and implementation of Web design standards, policies and procedures.

Work Experience

Current - Ongoing

September 2021 - current

Mar 2019 - April 2022

Click POS - Owner of the retail software

Designing developing and maintaining Click POS solution desktop app and mobile app **Tech used:** vb.net, nodejs, mssql, expo, push notifications, maintained updates, GPS locator etc The strongest point of the software is connection between multiple node servers and combined to centralized one for offering online orders

Hovo Tech

Full stack Developer (software engineer)

Designing architecture and implementation of a complete solution on real estate software Tech being used:

AWS including: cognito, nodejs (backend), code pipeline, mysql (rds), ec2, beanstalk, S3 Tools and Technology:

- Angular
- Node js (express)
- Third party services used in backend for Valuation Engine

Marseco Software AG

Full Stack Developer

Responsibilities and Contribution:

Senior Angular and .NET Core developer:

- Designing, developing, and coding web applications.
- Overseeing continuous integration, unit testing, and configuration.
- Developing and deploying .NET Core applications.
- Troubleshooting and debugging.
- Assisting and collaborating with other developers and IT staff.

Head of Mobile Development (react native):

- Work as team leader to build React Native iOS / Android applications for FullStack's clients
- Architect, build and maintain excellent React Native applications with clean code.
- Write unit and integration tests.
- Integrate third-party API's.
- Release applications to the Apple and Google Play stores.

Selected Projects:

Click POS - Desktop and Mobile

Retail software including reports, invoices, online synchronization, stock management, sales etc. The software has the ability to synchronize in real time with handheld application. The Click POS mobile app is currently being developed and has a lot of features like online ordering, waitress version of ordering, staff management, real time tracking of orders, and the client side of the application.

Aug 2017 - Mar 2019

Inspire 11

Senior Developer

Responsibilities and Contribution:

Development of/using:

- Native Android Apps.
- Mobile apps with React Native, Expo.
- Python.
- CI Scripting.
- SQL.
- Data processing/ETL.

Jan 2013 - Dec 2017

Struga Production

Video Editing

Responsibilities and Contribution:

Used technologies: Adobe Premiere CC, Photoshop, Adobe After Effects.

Dec 2011 - May 2012

Unixitech Solutions

Head of IT/Graphic Designer/Web Developer

Responsibilities and Contribution:

PHP web development, e-commerce development using API, JSON, XML, Dispatch – Micro Framework.

Sep 2011 - May2012

SEE University – Business Center

Web Developer/Graphic Designer

Responsibilities and Contribution:

Web development at seeu.edu.mk using Joomla, Dreamweaver, Corel Draw, Adobe Illustrator. Graphic designer of university events.

2011 - Jul 2021

99 Media

CEO

Responsibilities and Contribution:

Creator and developer at hosting company that offers hosting domains, web design, logo design

Used technologies: WordPress, WHMCS, API, JSON, PHP, Python, Ruby on Rails, React, AngularJS, React Native.

Sep 2010 – Jun 2011

SEE University - Business Center

Web Developer

Responsibilities and Contribution:

Web development and design.

Sep 2009 - Jun 2010

SEE University - IT Department

IT support Member

Responsibilities and Contribution:

Support using Corel Draw, Photoshop.

Technical Experience	
	Programming: Scripting: Cl Languages and Tools: React Native, React, AngularJS, Python, Ruby on Rails, PHP, JSON, XML, API, WHMCS, Dispatch – Micro Framework Graphic Design Tools: Adobe Premiere CC, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Dreamweaver, Corel Draw Additional: Joomla, Expo
Education	
2013 – 2015	Linnaeus University – Sweden Major: Social Media and Web Technologies, Master program
2011	Duna – Skopje, North Macedonia Major: Implementor of a Business software Ultima
2009 – 2012	South East European University – Tetovo, North Macedonia Major: Computer Sciences and Technologies, Bachelor degree
Honors	
Oct 1999 – Jul 2003	Graduated from High School summa cum laude.
Languages	
	Native Albanian Proficient English Proficient Macedonian Basic Swedish